

User Experience Designer

Chicago, Illinois

www.ianadamsdesign.com ianfranceadams@gmail.com 828.699.4071

## Projects

#### Dragonwell Tea & Coffee

An online tea and coffee shop ecommerce design project

- i Easy navigation and browsing
- i Engaging visual design
- i Effortless checkout process
- i Ample product detail

Case Study and Prototype www.ianadamsdesign.com/dragonwell.html

#### ShowBuddy

Concert and live-performance finding mobile app design

- i Fast and simple onboarding i Intuitive
  - i Intuitive, nonlinear browsing
- i Features based on user research

Case Study and Prototype <a href="www.ianadamsdesign.com/showbuddy.html">www.ianadamsdesign.com/showbuddy.html</a>

#### Orion

Responsive content storage and organization system design

- i Employed thorough wireframing process i Thoughtful branding
- i Coded up partial prototype in addition to InVision prototype

Case Study and Prototype www.ianadamsdesign.com/orion.html

## Skills Tools

User Stories Sketch Adobe XD User Flows Prototyping Zeplin LoFi/HiFi Wireframing Jira User Interface Design InVision Branding Balsamiq Visual Design UsabilityHub Optimal Workshop Sketching

User Research

Design Thinking

Competitive Analysis

Photoshop

Personas

A/B Testing

User Testing

Figma

Illustrator

Omnigraffle

HTML/CSS

JavaScript (basic)

Writing Git/Github

## Summary

Meticulous yet imaginative user-centered designer with experience in transportation and customer service. I'm especially drawn to the research and prototyping phases of the design process and interested in challenges within a range of products and industries.

# Work Experience

UX/UI Designer

VeoRide - Chicago, Illinois

August 2018 - July 2019

Revamped dockless micro-mobility share company's mobile app while applying the user-centered design process to continuously, incrementally improve the product experience for all involved

Full-Service Shopper and Delivery Driver

Instacart - Chicago, Illinois

February 2017- August 2018

Worked independently with sophisticated mobile technology to resolve problems swiftly and provide high levels of customer service

Regional Tanker Driver (CDL)

Schneider Bulk Carriers - Gary, Indiana

October 2015 - January 2017

Interacted safely and professionally with tractor-trailer and tanker equipment, delivering chemicals in industrial settings and using in-truck satellite technology to effectively communicate daily with dispatch

Customer Service Representative

Trust Risk Management Services - Chicago, Illinois

July 2013 - July 2015

Provided assuring experiences to insureds via daily workflow of phone calls and document processing using proprietary enterprise software

## Education

Bloc Designer Track

Immersive, mentor-led apprenticeship in UX/UI Design www.Bloc.io, 2017-2018

Bachelor of Arts in Music

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, 2012

Undergraduate Study in Guitar Performance
University of North Carolina School of the Arts
Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 2007 - 2009

#### Other Interests

Backpacking Hiking Camping Biking Traveling Geography
Photography Art Classical Music American Music History
Economics/Finance Health/Nutrition Philosophy Religion
German Japanese Culture Kendo Meditation Rinzai Zen
Buddhism